<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="Installation" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
>
    <info>
        <pubdate>$LastChangedDate: 2011-07-20 18:41:39 +0100 (mer., 20 july 2011)$</pubdate>
    </info>
    <refnamediv>
        <refname>Installation</refname>

        <refpurpose>Installation of the ProActive Scilab Connector Toolbox</refpurpose>

    </refnamediv>

    <refsection>
        <title>Introduction</title>


        <para>A typical deployment of ProActive Scheduler with Scilab can be seen on the diagram below:</para>
        <para>
            <inlinemediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="SchedulerScilab.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </inlinemediaobject>
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The local Scilab session will connect to the ProActive Scheduler.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The local user will submit a function "foo" to call with a set of parameters.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The Scheduler will select among all its resources, those suited to the job.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A Scilab engine will be started on each selected resource.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each foo(k) will be executed on remote engine.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Results will be forwarded back to the use
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </refsection>
    <refsection>
        <title>Downloading and Installing ProActive Scilab Toolbox and ProActive Scheduler</title>
        <para>Scilab Connector Toolbox can be downloaded from :
            <ulink url="http://www.activeeon.com/community-downloads">http://www.activeeon.com/community-downloads
            </ulink>
            and will be soon available on ATOMS with Scilab 6+ compatibility.
        </para>
        <para>
            After ProActive Scheduler and ProActive Scilab Connector are downloaded, unzip them in a directory e.g. D:\Scilab_Connector and
            D:\ProActive_Scheduling_server
        </para>
        <para>
            According to your deployment infrastructure,
            <emphasis>ProActive Scheduler</emphasis>
            must be installed on :
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The host which will launch the Scheduler.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each worker host used by the Scheduler.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>The prerequisite for using the ProActive Scheduler is a <emphasis>Java Virtual Machine</emphasis>. On the
            above list, machines must have a Java Virtual Machine installed and available on the Path of either cmd.exe for Windows or sh for
            linux. For many ProActive features it is also necessary to define the environment variable <literal>JAVA_HOME</literal>
            to the installation directory of the Java Virtual Machine.
        </para>
        <para>Complete configuration and installation of the ProActive Scheduler is beyond the scope of this help, for
            more information, refer to:
        </para>

        <para>
            <ulink url="https://doc.activeeon.com/latest/admin/ProActiveAdminGuide.html">ProActive Scheduler
                Manual
            </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Scilab Connector</emphasis>
            must be installed on :
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each client host which will connect to the Scheduler to submit Scilab functions.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </refsection>

    <refsection>
        <title>Automatic Configurations</title>
        <refsection>
            <title>Automatic search of Scilab installations for workers</title>
            <para>In the typical utilisation of the toolbox, no configuration of the worker host will be necessary for
                Scilab. When a scilab
                task is waiting to be executed on a scheduler worker, a script will be executed to locate automatically
                scilab on the host.
            </para>
            <para>
                The script will search for scilab in typical locations in both windows and linux environments and will
                write the scilab installations found in a configuration file which will be stored on the host. If no scilab installation
                is found, then the configuration file will be empty and the host will be assumed not to contain any scilab.
            </para>
            <para>Subsequent executions of
                Scilab will reuse this configuration file to decide whether a scilab task can be executed on the host or
                not (though
                it is possible to force a scilab research via execution options, see option
                <emphasis>ForceScilabSearch</emphasis>
                in <link linkend="Configuration">Configuring PAsolve behavior</link>).
            </para>

        </refsection>
    </refsection>
    <refsection>
        <title>Manual Configurations</title>
        <refsection>
            <title>Manual configuration of Scilab installations for workers</title>
            <para>It may happen though that on some hosts, Scilab is not installed in a typical location and the
                automatic script doesn't manage to find it. In that case it will be necessary to write a Scilab configuration file manually.
            </para>
            <para>A sample configuration file is located inside the
                <emphasis>Scilab_Connector/lib/worker</emphasis>
                folder under the name ScilabWorkerConfiguration.xml
            </para>
            <para>This file must be edited and put inside the
                <emphasis>addons</emphasis>
                directory of ProActive Scheduler on the server side and on
                every hosts that will be used as Scilab workers for which the automatic configuration didn't work.
            </para>
            <para>If the scheduler is installed in a single directory shared by all workers (via NFS for example), then
                only one ScilabWorkerConfiguration.xml
                file needs to be edited. The syntax of the file allows to create a configuration for several machine
                groups via wildcards
                that will match a machine's hostname or ipaddress, and as well several scilab installations for the same
                machine.
            </para>
            <para>Here is an example of ScilabWorkerConfiguration.xml :
            </para>
            <programlisting><![CDATA[<MatSciWorkerConfiguration>
    <MachineGroup hostname=".*">
        <scilab>
            <version>5.3.0</version> <!-- Scilab version (must be at least 5.3.0) -->
            <home>c:\Program Files\scilab-5.3.0</home> <!-- Scilab installation directory -->
            <bindir>bin</bindir>
            <command>Scilex.exe</command>
            <arch>32</arch>
         </scilab>
    </MachineGroup>
</ScilabInstallations>]]></programlisting>
            <para>Here is an explanation of tags used by this file:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>MachineGroup:</emphasis>
                        this defines the machines which are targeted by this configuration. Machines can be identified
                        by either
                        <emphasis>hostname</emphasis>
                        or<emphasis>ip</emphasis>. The syntax of hostname and ip attributes follow the Regular
                        Expression syntax
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>version:</emphasis>
                        the Scilab version installed in numeric format.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>home:</emphasis>
                        full path to scilab home directory.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>bindir:</emphasis>
                        relative path (from homedir) to scilab executable.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>command:</emphasis>
                        scilab executable name.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>arch:</emphasis>
                        scilab architecture used (32 or 64)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </refsection>
        <refsection>
            <title>Manual Installation of ProActive Scilab Connector Libraries to the ProActive Scheduler</title>
            <para>The content of the directory <literal>Scilab_Connector/lib/worker</literal> (not the directory itself, only the content) must be copied
                inside the <literal>addons</literal> directory of ProActive Scheduler and of every Scilab Worker which will be used as matlab workers.</para>
            <para>Manually installing the librairies used by Scilab Connector inside the scheduler reduces the overhead of transferring them each time through the network.</para>

        </refsection>
    </refsection>

    <refsection>
        <title>Terminating ProActive Scilab Connector</title>
        <para>To configure scilab in order to properly close the toolbox at the scilab exit,
            simply add the following lines to the <literal>scilab.quit</literal> file located in the <literal>etc</literal> folder of your scialb installation :
        </para>
        <screen>
            // PROACTIVE
            if isdef("ProActiveConnectorlib") then
            PAterminate();
            end
        </screen>

    </refsection>

    <refsection>
        <title>See Also</title>
        <simplelist type="inline">
            <member>
                <link linkend="Introduction">Introduction to the ProActive Toolbox</link>
            </member>
            <member>
                <link linkend="Startup">Starting and Connecting to ProActive Scheduler</link>
            </member>
            <member>
                <link linkend="Configuration">Configuring and Debugging the Scilab Connector jobs</link>
            </member>
        </simplelist>
    </refsection>

    <refsection>
        <title>Authors</title>

        <simplelist type="vert">
            <member>The ProActive Team, Fabien Viale</member>
        </simplelist>
    </refsection>
</refentry>