<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="Introduction" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
>
    <info>
        <pubdate>$LastChangedDate: 2011-07-20 18:41:39 +0100 (mer., 20 july 2011)$</pubdate>
    </info>
    <refnamediv>
        <refname>Introduction</refname>

        <refpurpose>Introduction to the ProActive Toolbox</refpurpose>

    </refnamediv>

    <refsection>
        <title>Introduction</title>


        <para>
            <emphasis>Scilab Connector Toolbox</emphasis>
            is a Scilab toolbox designed to provide interaction with the <emphasis>ProActive Scheduler</emphasis>, part
            of ProActive Parallel Suite.

            <emphasis>ProActive Parallel Suite</emphasis>
            is an innovative Open Source solution (OW2) for parallel, distributed, multi-core computing.

            ProActive features Java Parallel Programming seamlessly integrated with Scheduling and Resource Management.
            ProActive simplifies the programming and execution of parallel applications on Linux, Windows and Mac,
            together with the management of resources such as Desktop, Servers, Clusters, Enterprise GRIDs and Clouds.

            The objectives of Scilab Connector Toolbox are to provide you with tools that:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Allow you to run Scilab functions on remote computers.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Do not block the local Scilab session while remote results are being produced.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Allow you to seamlessly retrieve results when you need them, just as if the functions were run
                    locally.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Provide you detailed remote log/output information, altogether with errors if any occurred.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Allow automatic source transfer, data file transfer, and other configurable options.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Allow fault-tolerant/disconnected sessions where intermediate results are persistent.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </refsection>
    <refsection>
        <title>Usage</title>
        <para>Matlab Connector Toolbox is designed for both beginners
            and advanced users. There are basically two usage roles:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The <emphasis>scheduler administrator</emphasis>: responsible for ProActive Scheduler installation
                    on every machines, and the administration of ProActive Scheduler.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The <emphasis>toolbox user</emphasis>: who will simply use the installed toolbox to run scilab code
                    in parallel.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The basic requirements for the
            <emphasis>administrator</emphasis>
            is to have a standard Information Technology knowledge on windows or linux, for example:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Start programs on windows or linux using the command line shell (sh or bat).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Change environment variables on windows or linux.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Be confident with XML syntax.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Understand network protocols and principles.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Have a basic knowledge of Security principles such as asymetric key pairs, and accounts management
                    frameworks such as Ldap.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Have a basic knowledge of the Java Programming Language.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Have a basic knowledge of scripting languages such as Javascript, Python or Ruby.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The basic requirement for the
            <emphasis>toolbox user</emphasis>
            is to be able to write standard Scilab code. A few aspects must be kept in mind while designing functions
            that will be run remotely :
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Any reference to a file must be done using relative paths, excluding any use of '..' from the
                    current folder (any tree hierarchy higher than the current directory has no meaning remotely).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Files to be transferred to or from a remote worker must be declared explicitly through the
                    InputFiles and OutputFiles tasks information.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Paths must be written with a portable syntax (usage of filesep() is recommended).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Functions of any number of input parameters are accepted but number of output parameters must be
                    1.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Functions must be independent from each others executions. It is not possible to write tightly
                    coupled code with inter-dependant communications.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </refsection>
    <refsection>
        <title>What are the current limitations of Scilab Connector Toolbox?</title>
        <para>Known bugs and limitations are reported on ProActive Matlab/Scilab Connector's github web page:</para>
        <para><ulink url="https://github.com/ow2-proactive/connector-matlab-scilab/issues">https://github.com/ow2-proactive/connector-matlab-scilab/issues</ulink></para>




    </refsection>
    <refsection>
        <title>See Also</title>
        <simplelist type="inline">
            <member>
                <link linkend="Installation">Installation of the ProActive Scilab Connector Toolbox</link>
            </member>
        </simplelist>
    </refsection>
    <refsection>
        <title>Authors</title>

        <simplelist type="vert">
            <member>The ProActive Team, Fabien Viale</member>
        </simplelist>
    </refsection>
</refentry>