<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:id="ProActive_Scheduler_Scilab"><info><title>ProActive Scheduler's Scilab Extension</title></info>

		<section xml:id="Scheduler_Scilab_Overwiew"><info><title>Presentation</title></info>

			<para>
				<emphasis>Scilab</emphasis>
				is a scientific software for numerical computations.
				Developed since 1990 by researchers from INRIA and ENPC,
				it is now maintained and developed by Scilab Consortium
				since its creation in May 2003. Scilab includes hundreds
				of mathematical functions with the possibility to add
				interactively programs from various languages (C,
				Fortran...). It has sophisticated data structures
				(including lists, polynomials, rational functions,
				linear systems...), an interpreter and a high level
				programming language. Scilab works on most Unix systems
				(including GNU/Linux) and Windows (9X/2000/XP).
			</para>
			<para>
                The interface with Scilab inside ProActive comes as a Scilab Toolbox that can be directly accessed from the Scilab environment (ProActive Toolbox). The objectives of <emphasis>ProActive Toolbox</emphasis> are to provide you with tools that:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Allow you to run Scilab functions on remote computers.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Do not block the local Scilab session while remote results are being produced.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Allow you to seamlessly retrieve results when you need them, just as if the functions were run locally.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Provide you detailed remote log/output information, altogether with errors if any occurred.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Allow automatic source transfer, data file transfer, transfer of local Scilab workspace and other configurable options.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
		</section>

     <section xml:id="SciMat_Scilab_Installation">
        <info>
            <title>Installation for Scilab</title>
        </info>
         <para>A typical deployment of ProActive Scheduler with Scilab can be seen on the diagram below:</para>
                 <para>
                     <inlinemediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata fileref="images/png/matsci/SchedulerScilab.png"/>
                         </imageobject>
                     </inlinemediaobject>
                 </para>
                 <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>The local Scilab session will connect to the ProActive Scheduler.
                         </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>The local user will submit a function "foo" to call with a set of parameters.
                         </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>The Scheduler will select among all its resources, those suited to the job.
                         </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>A Scilab engine will be started on each selected resource.
                         </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>Each foo(k) will be executed on remote engine.
                         </para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>Results will be forwarded back to the use
                         </para>
                     </listitem>
                 </itemizedlist>
        <para>Scilab Connector Toolbox can be downloaded from <emphasis xlink:href="http://www.activeeon.com/community-downloads">http://www.activeeon.com/community-downloads</emphasis></para>
        <para>The package which must be downloaded is called <emphasis>Scilab_Connector</emphasis>. After downloading the package unzip it in a directory e.g. D:\Scilab_Connector</para>
        <para>
            The toolbox works only with Scilab version <emphasis>5.3</emphasis> and higher. The toolbox depends on another toolbox called <emphasis>Java Interaction Mechanism in Scilab</emphasis>(JIMS) which must be downloaded and installed from <emphasis>ATOMS</emphasis> before installing the Scilab Connector Toolbox.
        </para>
        <para>
            To install Scilab Connector Toolbox inside Scilab, the toolbox must be built and loaded inside Scilab via the standard Scilab toolboxes installation scheme.
            Below is the sequence of instructions from the scilab prompt to install it.
        </para>
        <para>At Scilab prompt, you first need to move to the toolbox root directory. Then you need to run "exec builder.sce", and "exec loader.sce" as shown underneath:</para>
      <screen><![CDATA[-->cd /home/fviale/scilab_connector_0.9/toolbox
 ans  =

 /home/fviale/scilab_connector_0.9/toolbox

-->exec builder.sce

-->mode(-1);

 Start ProActive
Building macros...

 Building macros  in /home/fviale/scilab_connector_0.9/toolbox/macros/
-- Création de [PAschedulerlib] (Macros) --
Attention:
L'identifiant : PASolveScilabGlobalConfig
 a été tronqué en : PASolveScilabGlobalConfi.

Building help...

Construit le document maître:
	/home/fviale/scilab_connector_0.9/toolbox/help

Building the manual file [javaHelp] in /home/fviale/scilab_connector_0.9/toolbox/help.
Generating loader.sce...
Generating cleaner.sce...

-->exec loader.sce

-->// This file is released under the 3-clause BSD license. See COPYING-BSD.

-->// Generated by builder.sce: Please, do not edit this file


-->try
--> getversion("scilab");
-->catch
--> error("Scilab 5.0 or more is required.");
-->end;


-->exec(get_absolute_file_path("loader.sce")+"etc/"+"toolbox_proactive.start");
Start Toolbox ProActive
	Load macros
	Load help

  ]]></screen>

        <para>
            If those steps were done successfully the toolbox will be available to use on Scilab. The detailed toolbox guide will also be loaded inside Scilab help at section "ProActive Scilab Connector"
        </para>
         <para>Please refer to the Scilab toolbox Help for a detailed explanation of ProActive Scilab Connector Toolbox usage.</para>
         <para>Alternatively you can either browse it online <emphasis xlink:href="../toolbox/help/en_US/scilab_en_US_help/index.html">here</emphasis></para>


    </section>

</chapter>
